# S Darshan

## **Android Developer**

## 6+ Years

https://darshn-dev.github.io

⋈ sdarshan.sn@gmail.com



Performance-driven and knowledgeable app developer with experience in improving performance, testing and updating existing app and developing new app functionalities. Conceptualized, designed, developed and deployed multiple android, iOS and web application. Armed with good problem solving, analytical and team managment skills, in addition to effective communication skills and passion to learn.

#### X Skills



## Familiar Technologies

Angular iOS TypeScript WebApp Development

## **Education**

MCA (2015) Manipal University - 7.28

BCA(2013) Manglore University - 80.84%

darshn-dev

in sdarshan13

# Work Experience

- Software Engineer, Ula, Bengaluru
  - Sept 2021 Nov 2022
  - Responsible for updating the existing code, fixing bugs, adding new features, publishing Logistic & Retailer multi-module app to the PlayStore
  - Took charge of increasing the crashfree users in the app which has more than 5 lakhs downloads.
  - Wrote unit tests, maintained the document for the implemented features
  - Collaborated with quality engineers, product manager, UI/UX team to ensure quality in all phases of app development

Android Developer, Quess Corp (Philips India - Client), Bengaluru Aug 2019 - Sept 2021

- Developed native android and iOS application that introduces medical professionals to the basics of Spectral CT physics and various spectral imaging features.
- Worked on Android and Web app to monitor a patient remotely. Integrated Twilio library to enable video calls between Android and Web app. Used various Bluetooth devices to fetch vital details by connecting to the app.
- Worked as the frontend developer for Philips Healthcare Cognition application. The hybrid application was developed for iOS and the web using Cordova.

App Developer / Fullstack developer, Kumudha Health Tech, Manipal May 2018 - May 2019

- Involed in the complete product development process.
- Designed, Developed, and deployed the fullstack web app using MERN stack. The web app is used to view the 3D model of the spinal cord. Integrated payment gateway to enable online payments.
- Led the project and Supervised, managed the team of interns.

## Lecturer, Sri Bhuvanendra College, Karkala

Dec 2017 - Apr 2018

- Prepared and delivered lectures to undergraducate students on C++, .net and Networking
- Assisted, supervised and introduced industry norms to the students in their project work.

Senior Associate, Atyati Technologies, Bengaluru

Aug 2015 - Aug 2017

- Developed native Android application to handle banking in villages.
- Helped the juniors and interns to consistently apply appropriate development principles and standards during all phases of the development life-cycle.
- Led the communication with the client

# Freelancing

Provided technical expertise in the product design at Navson Technologies. Built the android app completely from the scratch to communicate with Arduino device using bluetooth.

Developed and published local news aggregator app and reached 2k+ downloads within 2 weeks without any marketing